Guide to the Priscilla Tremper Leith Papers, 1974-1988
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Priscilla Tremper Leith Papers
1974-1988
Leith, Priscilla Marie Tremper, 1935-
2.4 cubic feet (4 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Correspondence, reports and other materials relating primarily to Leith’s work with the National Organization for Women.
Biographical Note
Priscilla Marie Tremper Leith, born 1935, graduated from Vassar College in 1956 with a mathematics major and went on to do graduate work in business at Babson College. Leith has worked as an accountant, tax preparer, and journalist, publishing 200 articles between 1975 and 1978. Addtionally, Leith held public office in Ward 4 of the Democratic Committee of Newton, Massachusetts from 1980 to 1982. She became a member of the National Organization for Women soon after it was founded, and held leadership positions in Massachusetts NOW chapters.
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence and other papers from NOW actions, meetings, and initiatives. Of particular interest are materials relating to the campaign for the Equal Rights Amendment, Walter Mondale’s 1984 Presidential campaign and the 1978 re-election campaign of Massachusetts Senator Edward Brooke. The collection includes letters from several notable politicians and activists, including Katherine Graham, Edward Kennedy, Robert Drinan, Edward Brooke, Thomas "Tip" O’Neill, as well as NOW Presidents Eleanor Smeal and Judy Goldsmith.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Woman Suffrage and Women's Rights Collection
Separated Materials
Some materials in the original Leith accession were added to the
Woman Suffrage and Women's Rights Collection
Subject Headings
Names:
Brooke, Edward William, 1919-
Organizations:
National Organization for Women
Subjects:
Equal rights amendments; Sex discrimination--Law and legislation--Massachusetts; Women in politics; Women's rights; Feminists--United States
VCL Categories
Politics; Women's History
Encoding Information
Encoded by Laura Streett, March 2008
Acquisition Information
Gift of Priscilla Tremper Leith, 2004.
Series List
- Series I. Correspondence
- Series II. Conference Materials
- Series III. Massachusetts NOW Bylaws
- Series IV. ERA Materials
- Series V. Campaign Materials
- Series VI. Massachusetts NOW State Council
- Series VII. Economic Justice Committee
- Series VIII. Miscellaneous
Container List
- SERIES I. Correspondence
  - Personal and Professional (Folder 1.1)
  - Official NOW Correspondence (Folder 1.2)
  - From Priscilla Leith (Folder 1.3)
- SERIES II. Conference Materials
  - 1975 National Conference (Folder 1.4)
  - 1975 National Conference (Folder 1.5)
  - 1978 National Conference (Folders 1.6-1.7)
  - 1979 National Conference (Folders 1.8-1.9)
  - 1981 National Conference (Folder 1.10)
  - 1982 National Conference (Folder 1.11)
  - 1983 National Conference (Folders 1.12-1.13)
  - 1984 National Conference (Folder 1.14)
  - 1985 National Conference (Folder 1.15)
  - 1985 National Conference (Folder 1.16)
  - Northeast Regional Conference, June 1977 (Folder 1.17)
  - Northeast Regional Conference, June 1979 (Folder 1.18)
  - Northeast Regional Conference, June 1980 (Folder 1.19)
  - Northeast Regional Conference, April 1986 (Folder 1.20)
  - Northeast Regional Conference, April 1988 (Folder 1.21)
  - Massachusetts NOW Conference, October 1985 (Folder 1.22)
  - San Antonio Conference, 1980 (Folder 1.23)
  - Eleanor Roosevelt Centennial Conference, 1984 (Folder 1.24)
  - Rhode Island Regional Meeting, Fall 1976 (Folder 1.25)
  - Kansas City Bylaws Conference, 1976 (Folder 1.25)
- SERIES III. Massachusetts NOW Bylaws
  - Massachusetts NOW Bylaws (Folders 1.26-1.30)
- SERIES IV. ERA Materials
  - ERA Notebooks, 1979-1981 (Folder 1.31)
  - AAVC and ERA, 1980 (Folder 1.32)
  - North Carolina ERA Ratification, 1982 (Folders 1.33-1.34)
  - ERA Boycott Resolution/Newton Board of Aldermen, 1978-1980 (Folder 1.35)
  - Illinois ERA Campaign, 1979 (Folder 1.36)
  - News Clippings/Mormon Opposition, 1979-1980 (Folder 1.37)
  - ERA Materials, 1979-1980 (Folder 1.38)
  - National Outreach Campaign Kit, 1980 (Folder 2.1)
  - ERA Materials, 1981-1982 (Folder 2.2)
  - ERA Background Information, 1980 (Folder 2.3)
  - ERA Extension Campaign, 1978 (Folder 2.4)
  - ERA Campaign, 1979 (Folder 2.5)
  - ERA Extension Resolution, 1978 (Folder 2.6)
- SERIES V. Campaign Materials
  - Brooke, 1978 (Folder 2.7)
  - Mondale, 1984 (Folder 2.8)
  - NOW Equality PAC, 1984 (Folder 2.9)
- SERIES VI. Massachusetts NOW State Council
  - Massachusetts NOW State Council, 1986 (Folder 2.10)
  - Massachusetts NOW State Council, 1978-1980 (Folders 2.11-2.13)
  - Massachusetts NOW State Council, 1984-1985 (Folder 2.14)
  - Massachusetts NOW State Council, 1983-1984 (Folder 2.15)
  - Massachusetts NOW State Council, 1983-1986 (Folder 2.16-2.19)
  - Massachusetts NOW State Council, 1987-1988 (Folder 2.20)
  - Lexington Area NOW, 1987 (Folder 2.21)
  - Lexington Area NOW, 1986-1988 (Folder 2.22)
  - Lexington Area NOW, 1977-1983 (Folders 2.23-2.25)
  - Massachusetts NOW, 1980-1981 (Folder 2.26)
  - State Council Papers, 1986-1988 (Folder 2.27)
  - State Council Papers, Fall 1986 (Folder 2.28)
  - State Council, 24 Apr 1988 (Folder 2.29)
  - State Council, May 1980 - Jan 1982 (Folders 2.30-2.31)
- SERIES VII. Economic Justice Committee
  - Economic Justice Committee, 1979-1980 (Folder 3.1)
  - Economic Justice Committee, 1980-1982 (Folder 3.2)
- SERIES VIII. Miscellaneous
  - Nametags, (7 items) (Box 3)
  - Guest Pass (Box 3)
  - Bumper Stickers (Box 3)
  - Photograph—Leith with Edward Kennedy (Box 3)
  - ERA Pin (Box 3)
  - Novelty Paper Clip (Box 3)
  - Audio Tape, (3 items) (Box 3)
  - NOW History/Socialist Workers' Party, 1977-1979 (Folder 4.1)
  - Media Materials, 1984-1986 (Folder 4.2)
  - Hussain Rape Case, 1981 (Folder 4.3)
  - Income and Insurance Materials, 1974 (Folder 4.4)
  - NOW Materials, 1978-1982 (Folder 4.5)
  - Calendars, 1981-1982 (Folder 4.6)
  - Leith's article on the ERA, Vassar Quarterly, 1982 (Folder 4.7)